Dara Anya

Houdini FX Artist

Email: daraanya@gmail.com Phone: +1(713)367-4871 Reel: https://vimeo.com/781365809 LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/dara-anya ArtStation: https://www.artstation.com/dara-anya GitHub: https://github.com/dara-anya

Summary

An experienced Houdini FX Artist who is educated and has worked in the fields of neuroscience, computer science, game production and visual effects. FX Artistry resonates with me as the coalescence of science, art and technology: an appreciation of life and the imagination and wonder to expand beyond reality. Let us wonder together.

Work Experience

Houdini FX Artist at Spruce Digital

July 2023 - Sept. 2023

- Researched and Developed waterFX for commercial project
- · Constructed timeline and shot breakdowns
- · Implemented feedback and submitted deliverables punctually

Houdini FX Artist at Impossible Objects

March 2023 - May 2023

- Created vellumFX for shoe reveal in Merrell "Skyfire 2" commercial
- Researched and Developed waterFX for beach scene in "Better Never Stops" Onstar commercial
- Implemented feedback, submitted deliverables punctually and updated FTrack

Motion Capture Cleanup Technician/Animator at Motion Capture Orlando

July 2022 - Sept. 2022

- · Cleaned, animated and supervised over 10 mocap sequences for Reallusion's "Run for Your Life" pack
- · Initialized motion capture Vicon system and marked performers
- · Liaised with CEO and updated ShotGrid to deliver sequences punctually

Web Developer/Project Manager at Resicom, Inc.

May 2018 - July 2022

- · Improved web design and updated project information
- Managed a \$300,000 City of Houston Clearing and Grubbing project
- Archived files and updated architectural plans for over six projects

Content Project Manager at HEADCASE

Sept. 2019 - Dec. 2019

- · Formed, developed and expanded business-client relations
- · Composed call sheets, shot lists, set-up and operated equipment and performed other production tasks, as needed
- · Completed and released projects for clients including Vodafone X, Renault, Mind Over Matter and Irish Distillers

Quality Assurance Supervisor/Compatibility Tester at Aspyr Media

July 2016 - Feb. 2018

- Performed certification sweeps and shipped over seven games including Mafia III and Civilization VI
- · Conducted and pitched concepts at stand-up meetings
- · Tested game functionality on combinations of hardware and software including Linux, Windows and OS systems

Research Experience

MEG Brain Scanning Technician Assistant at Dell Children's Medical Center Foundation

June 2016 - Aug. 2016

- · Conducted research to localize the onset of epileptic seizures in humans using MEG brain scanning
- Programmed and executed experiments using Stim2
- · Reviewed, critiqued and analyzed data from academic research materials

Research Assistant in Cognitive Psychology Lab at The University of Texas at Austin

Sept. 2012 - Dec. 2015

- Researched cognitive and translational neuroscience of decision making and category learning in humans using fMRI and EEG brain scanning
- Programmed experiments using Python and MATLAB (FSL View used for data analysis)
- · Reviewed and critiqued academic research materials

Research Assistant in Neuromuscular and Biomechanics Lab at The University of Houston

June 2014 - Aug. 2014

- Researched human ambulation under controlled stress using motion capture units, Vicon camera systems, force plates, loading cells, inertial measurement unit and video capture
- · Reviewed, proposed and critiqued academic research papers
- · Organized and analyzed data

Education

Certificate in Visual Effects

Jan 2022 - Dec. 2022

The Digital Animation & Visual Effects (DAVE) School

Bachelor of Science in Neuroscience

Aug. 2012 - May 2016

The University of Texas at Austin

Certifications

Certificate in Supervised Machine Learning

Jan. 2024 - Jan. 2024

Stanford University

Certificate in Full-Stack Web Development

Feb. 2018 - Feb. 2019

The University of Texas at Austin

Certificate in Elements of Computing in Python

The University of Texas at Austin

Jan. 2013 - May 2016

Sofware

Programming Languages

Skills

- Houdini
- Unreal
- Nuke
- Maya
- VICON
- Shogun
- iClone8
- Photoshop
- Substance

- Houdini VEX
- · Python
- Java
- JS/HTML/CSS

- Houdini FX: Flip, Pyro, Vellum, RBD, Muscles, Grooming, etc.
- · Houdini Digital Assets Creation
- Real-time FX: UE Niagara
- Real-time (Virtual) Production
- Pipeline Development: USD, Solaris, MaterialX, Metahumans
- Machine Learning
- Motion Capture
- Rigging/Animating
- Lighting/Compositing
- Research Development
- Critical and Creative Thinking
- Problem Solving
- Communication
- Project Management

Referees

Michael Keith - Director of Career Services, The DAVE School, MKeith@daveschool.com Joyce Cox - Producer & VFX Consultant, Zu2, Inc., zu2jmc@me.com Luc Delamare - Head of Technology, Impossible Objects, luc@impossible-objects.com Morgan McDermott - Head of VFX, Impossible Objects, morgan@impossible-objects.co PJ Salamon - Lead VFX Instructor, The DAVE School, psalamon@daveschool.com